Guide to the Alexander Haight family collection, 1764-1977
George Mason University Libraries
- Series 7: Oversize, 1863-1966; (1 box)
  This series includes Confederate bonds; a centennial print of the Declaration of Independence; and newspapers chronicling the sinking of the Titanic, the election of Franklin Roosevelt, and other historical events.
  - Confederate bonds (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - $500 bond, 1863; 1.
      signed bond notes on a 14" x 16" sheet of paper
    - $100 bond, 1863; 2.
      unsigned bond notes on a 14" x 16" sheet of paper
    - $500 bond, 1864; 3.
  - Gold miner's map, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Reproduction of the US Declaration of Independence for the Centennial Memorial, 1876 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Obituaries, 1905-1915 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    includes an obituary for Colonel John Mosby in the Mount Kisko News
  - Washington Times article on the sinking of the Titanic, April 19, 1912 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Gazette on the election of Franklin Roosevelt, October 19, 1934 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Chronology pages from Virginia Page News and Courier, 1938-1939 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Northern Virginia Daily on Lyndon Johnson on Vietnam, April 1, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Series 8: Objects, 1860s; (10 boxes)
  This series contains Civil War Artifacts as well as ancient American Indian arrowheads and tools. The Civil War artifacts include three muskets, ammunition, a sword with scabbard, two bayonets, a cavalry bridle, and a hand-made crutch.
  - .58 caliber bullets, 3 ringers, 1860s (Box 10, Folder 1)
    16 bullets; all of the bullets in this series were found on Haight property after the Civil War
  - .69 caliber bullets, 3 ringers, 1860s (Box 10, Folder 2)
    7 bullets
  - .69 caliber prussian bullet, 1860s (Box 10, Folder 3)
    1 bullet
  - Pistol bullets, 1860s (Box 10, Folder 4)
    4 bullets
  - Enfield miniballs, 1860s (Box 10, Folder 5)
    7 miniballs
  - Picket stake with loop missing, 1860s (Box 10, Folder 6)
    picket stakes like this were used to tie horses
  - Unidentified tool, 1860s (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - US Cavalry bridal, 1860s (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - US cartridge box shoulder strap breast plate, 1860s (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - US enlisted man's belt buckle, 1860s (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Cavalry saber belt buckle with silver trim, 1860s (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - US cartridge box flap plate, 1860s (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - English shake buckle, 1860s (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Powder horn, stop missing, 1860s (Box 11, Folder 8)
    used to hold gunpowder
  - American Indian artifacts, pt. I (Box 12)
    13 envelopes containing stone arrowheads and knives, probably excavated from Haight property, which include labels claiming origins from 8,000 BCE - 3,500 BCE
  - American Indian artifacts, pt. II (Box 13)
    6 envelopes containing stone arrowheads and knives, probably excavated from Haight property
  - American Indian artifacts, pt. III (Box 14)
    21 rocks, 1 seashell, and 1 envelope with large iron nails
  - Union spurs, 1860s (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Shell fragment, 1860s (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Union officer's spur, 1860s (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Colt pistol mold for .31 caliber bullets, 1860s (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Canteen, 1860s (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Bullet holder, 1860s (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Awl, 1860s (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Button, 1860s (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - .45 caliber rifle cartridge, 1860s (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Bullet, used, 1860s (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Keepsake, 1860s (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Unidentified, 1860s (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Horse's bit, 1860s (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Tin primer caps, 1860s (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Cash box, 1860s (Box 18)
  - Shells, 1860s (Box 19)
    2 heavy artillery shells
  - Camp stool, 1860s
  - Hand-made crutch, 1860s
  - Cooking kettle and tripod, 1860s
  - 3 muskets: 1860 Genuine Virginia, 1860s
  - Fire tongs, 1860s
  - Sword with scabbard, 1860s
  - 2 bayonets, 1860s
  - 2 larger bayonets or swords, 1860s
    2.5 to 3 feet long